IVAN ALVAREZ (917) 937-1192 | <u>alvarivan88@gmail.com</u> | github.com/Alvarian/INTR

## **SUMMARY PROFILE:**

Successful experience as a website developer and electrician. Accomplished and technically skilled with all facets of website design and development. Experienced with mitigating intricate nuances that could disrupt the optimum effectiveness of computer and electrical systems. Astute ability to interpret intricate technical documents. Experienced with operating, inspecting and repairing a wide range of computer and electrical equipment. Possess outstanding technical, analytical, decision making and interpersonal skills. Extremely attentive to details. Adept at multitasking, working under pressure and adhering to strict deadlines. Proficient with procuring and allocating resources appropriately for various projects, working effectively in coordinating tasks with team members and superior completion of projects.

## **CORE CREDENTIALS**

Coding languages: HTML, Vanilla.js, Node.js, CSS, PHP, Three.js, Angular.js, Vue.js and React.js.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

Back End Website Developer | LETS STRUT | October 2017 to November 2017

www.github.com/Alvarian/lestrut

- Collaborated with colleagues to creatively and assiduously develop, design and enhance a website for a LGBT blog that covers a vast array of social and political topics.
- Utilized Vanilla Javascript and Firebase to effectively develop the back end of the website.
- Incorporate various tools to augment the smooth operation and technical efficiency of the website.
- Employ various resources to ensure that the website is user friendly, visually appealing and informative.

Residential Electrician | SWIFT CLEANERS – New Rochelle, NY | February 2017 to March 2017

- Performed a myriad of electrical installation assignments for the renovation of a commercial facility.
- Interfaced with senior management officials and employees to maintain efficiency, quality work production and elite job performance.
- Prepared budgets for material expenses in accordance with project requirements, and monitored expenditures.

Commercial Electrician | HORSE POWER ELECTRIC - Brooklyn, NY | July 2016 to December 2016

- Fabricated, installed, tested and maintained wiring, control panels and electrical components for a newly constructed 72 story commercial high-rise building.
- Inspected electrical systems, components and equipment to identify defects and hazards, assess the need to eradicate marginal errors in the infrastructure's circuits and ensure compliance with regulatory codes.
- Ensured that safety guidelines were adhered to at all times, in accordance with prescribed regulations.

Sales Clerk | DUANE READE – Manhattan, NY | January 2013 to July 2016

- Interfaced with manager to implement the sales operations of the store, including ordering products and supplies, performing inventory, labeling sales items and facilitating financial transactions at the register.
- Assisted with the merchandising operations of the store.
- Provided clients with outstanding service and support by answering inquiries, rectifying discrepancies with product performance and/or purchases and ensuring complete customer satisfaction.

# **EDUCATION**

General Assemblies: Completed 500 Hour Certificate for Website Development | 2017.

Berk Trade & Business: Completed 600 Hour Certificate for Electrical Installations | 2016.

Technical Career Institute: Completed Courses Aligned with an Associate's for Industrial Electronics | 2015

Regents Diploma Obtained | Bronx High School for the Visual Arts | 2009